climate change is one of the greatest
issues of our time and it affects the
decisions we make every day what we buy
how we invest and how we plan for
retirement
the international energy agency
estimates the world must invest four
trillion dollars annually from 2026 to
2030 in low carbon energy efficiency and
carbon removal to reach net zero
emissions by
2050 at manulife we're doing our part
[Music]
manulife is a leading international
financial services provider we're the
10th largest insurer and a top 25 global
money manager our mission is quite
simply decisions made easier lives made
better those six words resonate in every
aspect of our impact agenda which is
built on three interconnected areas of
focus empowering sustained health and
well-being driving inclusion and
economic opportunity and accelerating a
sustainable future in our operations
we are proud to be net zero already
however we know we need to do more and
we have committed to reducing our
absolute emissions 35 percent by 2035.
from an investment perspective we are
committed to steering our portfolio
to be net zero by 2050 and we are
working on shorter term targets across
our most carbon intensive sectors we are
committed to the science-based target
initiative to guide and validate our
target setting measurement and progress
reporting from a product and services
perspective we'll drive innovation
toward our impact first products
providing opportunities for our clients
and customers to be part of the solution
to climate change
[Music]
we can help the transition to net zero
emissions by investing in renewable
energy more efficient real estate and
natural responses to climate change in
the timber and agriculture area
manulife recently invested in silicon
ranch
one of the largest independent power
producers in the us it specializes in
renewable energy solutions
and we have our eye on other exciting
and emerging investment areas too like
hydrogen or carbon capture technologies
and the broader use of offshore wind
technology
manulife provided an equity loan to the
majority owners of the watanikini app
power transmission project first nation
limited partnership
watanakini app power is building 1800
kilometers of power transmission lines
in northern ontario canada
the indigenous lead project is majority
owned by 24 first nation communities in
partnership with fortis inc and other
private investors
this project will supply clean reliable
energy to thousands of residents and
reduce the reliance on costly and
environmentally risky diesel generation
not only will it create up to 1300
construction jobs but also results in
over 6.6 million tons of avoided carbon
dioxide over 40 years
manulife is a life insurance company and
sustainability agenda is very high on
our minds as such we have been investing
in green or sustainable assets
for a number of years green assets are
environmentally friendly assets that
help support our transition to a
low-carbon economy naturally on our
balance sheet we had 40 billion dollars
or so of assets that would qualify as
sustainable manulife decided to launch
the very first green bond by a global
life insurance company we raised half a
billion singapore dollars in singapore
in 2017 the funds were used towards a
revered mulen project wind farms in our
province of quebec in canada and solar
energy project in ontario a year later
in 2018 we came to the canadian market
with the issuance of canadian dollar 600
million that funded our renewable energy
projects as well as sustainably managed
forests in canada the united states and
uruguay our issuances of two green bonds
contribute over 190 000 times in
reduction of co2 every year the primary
objective of the general account is to
match our assets to our liabilities to
ensure that we can pay out our life
insurance premium what we do is we
collect funds from shareholders debt
holders and policyholders and invest
those fronts in a variety of different
asset classes across the globe
traditionally you have your finance team
on one side doing its own thing and then
the sustainability team on another side
doing its own thing what a sustainable
debt issuance does is that it brings
these two teams together within the
general account of manulife what we've
done to foster this is that we've
actually created an internal climate
change working group the idea is
essentially just to meet up for about an
hour a week where we share best
practices and promote a culture where we
decide on how to best move forward
towards our sustainability pledges as
well as how we can better improve our
sustainability actions
i'm incredibly proud of the impact and
progress that our team is making on this
journey
but there's so much more to be done
achieving a maximum temperature increase
of 1.5 degrees celsius by the year 2050
will require
3.5 times more renewable energy than
current levels failure to meet these
goals will result in reduced prosperity
around the world and that's exactly why
we'll continue to take action with our
partners to invest in impactful and
innovative solutions and to me there's
no higher calling